<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-15T23:21:26+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">adityabhushan.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">Be Grateful and Cherish the good things people say about you</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/17/thanks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Be Grateful and Cherish the good things people say about you" /><published>2013-06-17T12:34:00+05:30</published><updated>2013-06-17T12:34:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/17/thanks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/17/thanks.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I always prefer to keep a track of the good things people say about me. Remembering then helps me to overcome my lows, Below are some of the things which i was able to document
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note info&quot;&gt;
&quot;I envy you, you are always able to do whatever you want, without the fear of what others might think about you&quot; - Raghu Mohan during a conversation
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;note info&quot;&gt;
&quot;hey wanted 2 say sumthing u have lot of talent hardly met such person ..kp learnin !!&quot; - Dhara Manek on FB
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;note info&quot;&gt;
&quot; u inspire me back.. &quot; - Nikhil Kulkarni on a FB Chat
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;note info&quot;&gt;
&quot;Your Energy and Enthusiasm are amazing! How passionate you get about what you do is inspiring. it has been amazing getting to know you.&quot; - Sarah Bass
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;note info&quot;&gt;
the guy whose world revolves around Quora, Steve Jobs and books! Retain your..ummm…weirdness man! I have a feeling it will take you far. Keep reading, keep coding!  - Ganesh Nagarsekar on a post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://ganeshnagarsekar.wordpress.com/2013/06/28/yourstory-is-awesome-so-thats-that/&quot;&gt;YourStory&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will keep updating them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">I always prefer to keep a track of the good things people say about me. Remembering then helps me to overcome my lows, Below are some of the things which i was able to document &quot;I envy you, you are always able to do whatever you want, without the fear of what others might think about you&quot; - Raghu Mohan during a conversation</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Push Yourself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/03/push.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Push Yourself" /><published>2013-06-03T19:36:00+05:30</published><updated>2013-06-03T19:36:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/03/push</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/03/push.html">&lt;p&gt;when you hit gym for the first time, you are told to do basic work out, then slowly as you get accustomed, the trainer asks you to increase your sets and also the number of reps in each set. now if keep doing the same for few days you get bored and tend to push yourself by trying out new combinations and experimenting.
same happens with our body,  mind, attitude and aptitude as well. when all four of these work together and the attitude towards the goal forces the body to work hard and mind to take over when the body says it can’t take anymore, we slowly and steadily develop an aptitude for that task which was perceived as difficult and impossible sometime back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when we try to push our limits every day we are actually expanding our comfort zone. which helps us in achieving goals we have never ever imagined. i know people who run marathons and had started with a normal walk and a goal to push their limits. ultra marathoners run around 200 kilometers at a time.and believe me they are no different than us, they eat the same food as we. only difference is that they are more focused and have running as an activity where they give their 100 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vijay Yallurkar is a good friend of mine who started running with 10 kilometers and now can run for over 70 kilometers comfortably. he has built the amazing stamina by practicing for a year and constantly expanding his comfort zone, i look at him as an inspiration and constantly seek motivation from him.
where do you look for inspiration?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">when you hit gym for the first time, you are told to do basic work out, then slowly as you get accustomed, the trainer asks you to increase your sets and also the number of reps in each set. now if keep doing the same for few days you get bored and tend to push yourself by trying out new combinations and experimenting. same happens with our body, mind, attitude and aptitude as well. when all four of these work together and the attitude towards the goal forces the body to work hard and mind to take over when the body says it can’t take anymore, we slowly and steadily develop an aptitude for that task which was perceived as difficult and impossible sometime back.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minimalism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/03/minimal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minimalism" /><published>2013-06-03T19:36:00+05:30</published><updated>2013-06-03T19:36:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/03/minimal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/06/03/minimal.html">&lt;p&gt;How being minimal can help you (and the world) as well.
few months back in one of the events i attended, i met a lady from Singapore who came with the luggage of the world (her suitcase was so big that i could have easily fit in) she wanted a place to keep her suitcase safely. Being the gentleman i am, it is understood that i helped the lady find a place for her suitcase and helped her with it(it was extremely heavy). but i always wondered what was in the suitcase that she had to &lt;b&gt;carry the worries of the entire kashmir in it&lt;/b&gt;. That was my eureka moment for a new project on minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Minimalism is a low consumption way of living&lt;/b&gt;. the reason i follow minimalism and try to be minimal is to decrease my dependence on things and also help reduce consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has long been observed that the less things we are dependent upon, the less we have to worry about, in turn the happier we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;currently i have given up using a watch(It was a very difficult decision) from past three months. My ultimate goal is to strip down to less than 10 items (including the Number of clothes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is meant to go on for 100 days but will be happy to carry it forward as go on for as long as i like.
currently my frequently  used stuff consists of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1) 5 pairs of cloths (one for each day of the week)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;2) 2 pair of socks&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;3) 1 pair of shoes&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;4) 1 laptop&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;5) 1 Digital camera&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;6) 1 Notebook&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;7) 1 Pen&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;8) 1 Bag to carry everything (I do not use plastic covers)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;9) 1 Motorcycle (I walk to work/use public transport on weekends)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;10) A dongle for Internet (&lt;strike&gt;Borrowed&lt;/strike&gt;, Bought) &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;11) Cell Phone &lt;strike&gt;with 2G Internet connection (I use GPS to measure distances while walking)&lt;/strike&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;12) A pair of Ray Ban Aviator sunglasses&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strike&gt;13) 3 Pairs of Cuff Links (used rarely)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;14) 2 Pairs of Ascots (used rarely)&lt;/strike&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
&lt;b&gt;Most of the things i share from people thus initiating conversations and making good friends at various occasions.&lt;/b&gt;
Here is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.storyofstuff.org/movies-all/story-of-stuff/&quot;&gt;something for you, which will show you how when something is created a lot of waste is added to the environment along with some intangible byproducts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">How being minimal can help you (and the world) as well. few months back in one of the events i attended, i met a lady from Singapore who came with the luggage of the world (her suitcase was so big that i could have easily fit in) she wanted a place to keep her suitcase safely. Being the gentleman i am, it is understood that i helped the lady find a place for her suitcase and helped her with it(it was extremely heavy). but i always wondered what was in the suitcase that she had to carry the worries of the entire kashmir in it. That was my eureka moment for a new project on minimalism.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">If your life were a book</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/05/23/book.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="If your life were a book" /><published>2013-05-23T19:36:00+05:30</published><updated>2013-05-23T19:36:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/05/23/book</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/05/23/book.html">&lt;p&gt;If your life were a book how would like the first chapter to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are walking down the street after a tiring day at your office, you think that the day is finally over finally you are going to meet your spouse/girlfriend and waiting to tell her how your day was and suddenly you are hit by an oncoming vehicle and you are on your deathbed. what would you wish for, would you be happy that you are about to die without doing what you loved,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lived your life how your parents, friends and neighbors expected you to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;knowing that the money you accumulated in your banks will not be able to buy you an hour of extra life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;how many people will come at your funeral&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;how many lives have you impacted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one way to check this out is to call people whom you consider your friends and make a request which causes them to get out of their comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;well if your answer to above questions is no. what you can do is to make a bucket list and keep it in your conscious mind and strive to tick it off one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;somebody said sometime back that if you want to be great &lt;i&gt;“either write things worth reading or do things worth writing”.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;choice is your’s do you want your book to start with -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;Long time ago there lived a man/woman who was born, lived his life just like everybody, was struck in corporate job which he was about to leave since he joined it and died in a traffic accident/from some disease. he did not change any life, nor did he do what he wanted for the sake of his family, he did not go for bungee jumping though he talked a lot about it. he wanted to open a school also he wanted to impact a lot of lives by providing access to free health care, he wanted, he wanted and he died just wanting to change the world.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
or would you like to read it this way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;This book is about a man who changed the way people see things, he changed and impacted the lives of uncountable people, he lived life on his own terms and did what he wanted to do, he faced a lot of hurdles and challenges but he marched ahead and didn't let anything deter him, he had achieved what he wanted to achieved and created a better world, the world mourns his passing.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;its never too late to make a choice.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">If your life were a book how would like the first chapter to be</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Following up is not spam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/05/06/spam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Following up is not spam" /><published>2013-05-06T19:36:00+05:30</published><updated>2013-05-06T19:36:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/05/06/spam</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/05/06/spam.html">&lt;p&gt;Few days back I was at a product launch where we met many interesting people, exchanged a lot of business cards when a gentleman asked me what am I going to do with all those business cards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I will write to them all and follow up with them”, I Said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“oh! so you are going to spam their inbox.”, said the gentleman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(well I am probably not thinking of stacking them up and forget about them after six months nor do I plan to use them as face wipes or use these cards to scratch my back)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to explain to him about the use of business cards and how you make lasting personal and professional relationships if you use them in the right manner.
Let’s see how we can use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Purpose of the business cards&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question which comes to my mind is, why do we need business cards at first place? well what they contain is our name, what we do,  which organization do we belong to and our contact details.
well most of these things we normally state whenever we meet somebody and regarding contacting them, A facebook search can do wonders. so back to square one why do we need business cards? maybe we can use them to showcase our creativity or just because everybody does so or because we don’t want to be tongue tied when somebody asks us for our card. well all of us have our own reasons for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We exchanged cards, what now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;well we met and exchanged our cards, but what do we do after this. most of do not know how to follow up from here. what I do is just write a simple follow up mail and hit send. well the perplexing question is “what should I write in the mail when I don’t have anything to talk about (I don’t have any favor to ask him for currently, I will write to him when I need something)”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well if you don’t have to ask for something, you have a lots to offer to the other person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My strategy is to write about the context and build up on the conversation I had when meeting the other person. here is a sample of what you can write to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
Hi/Dear XYZ,
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It was nice to meet you at ABC event, (insert an interesting line or two from the conversation or anything special/appreciative about them which caught your attention)
&lt;br /&gt;
(let them know how you can offer to help them achieve their goals).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
your signature.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Advantages of Following up&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Very few people write follow up mails. (It shows that out of hundreds of people whom they met only you’ve taken the effort to write to the other person and you are genuinely interested in them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) you are offering to help them which will help you earn a brownie point and will be useful, don’t worry most of the times they don’t need your help what counts is you’ve offered to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) whenever you need to connect with them in future you can carry on/continue on the same thread which again reminds them of your association. I am sure if you receive a mail from someone whom you gave your card 3  months ago, there is a high probability that you will not even be able to recollect anything about the person. but if you would’ve received a mail from the person appreciating you or mentioning a positive point about you, you will immediately recollect the conversation and will be more than willing to help the person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if I don’t receive a reply from the person&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a big deal, probably this is the first time they have received a follow up mail from someone and they are as confused as how and what should they say in the reply to your mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Spam is the use of electronic messaging systems to send unsolicited bulk messages, especially advertising, indiscriminately. While the most widely recognized form of spam is e-mail spam, the term is applied to similar abuses in other media.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warning: Don’t worry you are not spamming any one, don’t try to use one format suits all or anything which even remotely fits the above definition.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">Few days back I was at a product launch where we met many interesting people, exchanged a lot of business cards when a gentleman asked me what am I going to do with all those business cards?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Do you Take time out for yourself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/01/10/time.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do you Take time out for yourself" /><published>2013-01-10T12:34:00+05:30</published><updated>2013-01-10T12:34:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/01/10/time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2013/01/10/time.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last year one day before my birthday one of my friends called me asked “is your birthday today or tomorrow?” it came as a realization and wakeup call to me that i had forgotten my birthday (Not exactly forgotten, but the excitement which builds up prior to your birthday wasn’t there) it made me realize that i had been working too hard and i need to give time to myself. well i started doing so and made it a top priority over everything i do.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Taking time out for yourself is one of the biggest favors you ever can do to yourself. it helps you rejuvenate, and think things out. even if you are not the one who likes to think and contemplate still you can take the time out and go for a walk alone or read a good book, just make sure you are not disturbed by anyone or anything. you can talk to yourself. or work on your pet projects, or just indulge in a hobby or some harmless reading but the point is to be alone for some time when you are not interacting with anyone but yourself, this will help you grow and moreover you will develop new skills which will help you in the long run.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Personally i prefer to take a long walk or read most of the time, when i am done with reading i learn new programming languages and technologies, it helps me grow as a hacker and also become aware in terms of knowledge and forming opinions on various things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">Last year one day before my birthday one of my friends called me asked “is your birthday today or tomorrow?” it came as a realization and wakeup call to me that i had forgotten my birthday (Not exactly forgotten, but the excitement which builds up prior to your birthday wasn’t there) it made me realize that i had been working too hard and i need to give time to myself. well i started doing so and made it a top priority over everything i do. Taking time out for yourself is one of the biggest favors you ever can do to yourself. it helps you rejuvenate, and think things out. even if you are not the one who likes to think and contemplate still you can take the time out and go for a walk alone or read a good book, just make sure you are not disturbed by anyone or anything. you can talk to yourself. or work on your pet projects, or just indulge in a hobby or some harmless reading but the point is to be alone for some time when you are not interacting with anyone but yourself, this will help you grow and moreover you will develop new skills which will help you in the long run. Personally i prefer to take a long walk or read most of the time, when i am done with reading i learn new programming languages and technologies, it helps me grow as a hacker and also become aware in terms of knowledge and forming opinions on various things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why you should make a bucket list</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/11/13/bucket.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why you should make a bucket list" /><published>2012-11-13T12:34:00+05:30</published><updated>2012-11-13T12:34:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/11/13/bucket</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/11/13/bucket.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Few days back I watched a Movie “bucket list”, it was a pretty good movie and the idea has been copied into several languages (Indian version is known as “Dasvidaniya”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is about having your wishes and fulfilling them. It also gives you motivation to be unconventional. to do something you have dreamt of when you were eight years young and had unrealistic laughable dreams, when i was eight i wanted to be a fighter pilot. later wanted to be an astronaut and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole idea behind the bucket list is to rediscover yourself and work towards the goals which you always wanted to achieve as a child and do that one step at a time. Here is my bucket list more will be added to it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sky Diving, Scooba Diving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Travel across the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Living a Minimalist Life (Maximum 10 Items)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Spending a week without money and other necessities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Educating an unprivileged child&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Meet Shri Atal Bihari Vajpayee, Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Climb a Volcano, Travel to Antarctica&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strike&gt;Meet Field Marshal SHFJ Manekshaw &lt;/strike&gt;(Unfortunately He Passed Away in Jun 2008)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Own a Stock Brokerage Firm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Start An Educational Institution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Work in a Non Profit &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Join Politics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Fall in Love&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; White Water Rafting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Bungee Jumping from a Cliff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Run a Complete Marathon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Complete a Four Deserts Race&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Own a Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Direct a Movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A 1000+ Km Road Trip By Bike&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Give a TED Talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Appear on the Cover of TIME Magazine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Do ping me, if you think i can help you with your list.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">Few days back I watched a Movie “bucket list”, it was a pretty good movie and the idea has been copied into several languages (Indian version is known as “Dasvidaniya”).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How do we perceive people and form their identities.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/09/14/identity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How do we perceive people and form their identities." /><published>2012-09-14T12:34:00+05:30</published><updated>2012-09-14T12:34:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/09/14/identity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/09/14/identity.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since I left the cubicle life, i have been meeting a lot of brilliant and smart people online and offline. hearing about their ideas and plans to take over the world with their products and things they are building and planning to build. one of the best things it taught me was never to judge any one by how they look or by what they say or by what they wear or any other criteria. I know it’s very easy to say that but very difficult to practice. When you start practicing something for a long duration it becomes a habit. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It helps to get the best things from every person without any preconceived notions about them and thus helps a lot when you talk to them since what we think about a person dictates how we behave around them.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How do you behave around people with whom you are not comfortable with?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">Since I left the cubicle life, i have been meeting a lot of brilliant and smart people online and offline. hearing about their ideas and plans to take over the world with their products and things they are building and planning to build. one of the best things it taught me was never to judge any one by how they look or by what they say or by what they wear or any other criteria. I know it’s very easy to say that but very difficult to practice. When you start practicing something for a long duration it becomes a habit. It helps to get the best things from every person without any preconceived notions about them and thus helps a lot when you talk to them since what we think about a person dictates how we behave around them. How do you behave around people with whom you are not comfortable with?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Generalist or Fickle Minded</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/09/14/generalist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Generalist or Fickle Minded" /><published>2012-09-14T12:34:00+05:30</published><updated>2012-09-14T12:34:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/09/14/generalist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifehacks/2012/09/14/generalist.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I did my first job as a Data entry operator when i was 15. a year later I repaired computers. I worked as a salesman in many supermarkets along with performing in theatre when i was 17. Acted in a south Indian movie as junior artist, reverse engineered software and wrote viruses at eighteen, taught tuition to kids and fought with college management for better education at nineteen ( close enough to getting expelled) conducted workshops at 21,
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Quite some time back i was speaking to a friend whom i had met only once and communicated very few times. this person is of the same age as me, we were talking about our experiences and also happened to talk about our journey so far. both of us shared a common concern, based on our experiences and things we have done, people tend to believe that we are much older than what we seem to be and suddenly when they come to know about our age, their reaction changes and suddenly we tend to descend from the overachiever to fickle minded person who can’t hold on to one thing for long.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I believe that learning multiple skills helps in a long term as compared to being a specialist in a field as this helps you to change tracks and do whatever you want and explore more in every sector wherever you plan to move on and learning a bit of every sector thus helping you to interact with a lot of people from every walk of life.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What do you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="LifeHacks" /><summary type="html">I did my first job as a Data entry operator when i was 15. a year later I repaired computers. I worked as a salesman in many supermarkets along with performing in theatre when i was 17. Acted in a south Indian movie as junior artist, reverse engineered software and wrote viruses at eighteen, taught tuition to kids and fought with college management for better education at nineteen ( close enough to getting expelled) conducted workshops at 21, Quite some time back i was speaking to a friend whom i had met only once and communicated very few times. this person is of the same age as me, we were talking about our experiences and also happened to talk about our journey so far. both of us shared a common concern, based on our experiences and things we have done, people tend to believe that we are much older than what we seem to be and suddenly when they come to know about our age, their reaction changes and suddenly we tend to descend from the overachiever to fickle minded person who can’t hold on to one thing for long. I believe that learning multiple skills helps in a long term as compared to being a specialist in a field as this helps you to change tracks and do whatever you want and explore more in every sector wherever you plan to move on and learning a bit of every sector thus helping you to interact with a lot of people from every walk of life. What do you prefer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Things to do Before I Die</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2012/08/29/bucket-list.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things to do Before I Die" /><published>2012-08-29T23:19:00+05:30</published><updated>2012-08-29T23:19:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2012/08/29/bucket-list</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2012/08/29/bucket-list.html">&lt;p&gt;I Always Thought of Putting up a Bucket List of Things I Wanted to Do, And see how Much I can Accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1)      &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; title=&quot;Parachuting&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parachuting&quot; rel=&quot;wikipedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sky Diving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2)      Scooba Diving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3)      Hitch Hicking across the Country&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4)      Living a Minimalist Life (Maximum 10 Items)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5)      Spending a week without money and other necessities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6)      Educating an unprivileged child&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7)      Meet Shri &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; title=&quot;Atal Bihari Vajpayee&quot; href=&quot;http://www.atalbiharivajpayee.in&quot; rel=&quot;homepage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Atal Bihari Vajpayee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8)      Meet &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; title=&quot;A. P. J. Abdul Kalam&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A._P._J._Abdul_Kalam&quot; rel=&quot;wikipedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9)      Meet &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; title=&quot;Lance Armstrong&quot; href=&quot;http://www.lancearmstrong.com/&quot; rel=&quot;homepage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lance Armstrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10)   Meet Field Marshal SHFJ Manekshaw (Unfortunately He Passed Away in Jun 2008)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11)   Own a &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; title=&quot;Stock broker&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stock_broker&quot; rel=&quot;wikipedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stock Brokerage&lt;/a&gt; Firm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12)   Start An Educational Institution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13)   Work in a &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; title=&quot;Nonprofit organization&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonprofit_organization&quot; rel=&quot;wikipedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Non Profit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; title=&quot;Non-governmental organization&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-governmental_organization&quot; rel=&quot;wikipedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NGO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14)   Join Politics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15)   Fall in Love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16)   &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; title=&quot;Rafting&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rafting&quot; rel=&quot;wikipedia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;White Water Rafting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17)   Bungee Jumping from a Cliff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18)   Run a Complete Marathon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19)   Complete Four Deserts Race&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20)   Own a Library&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21)   Direct a Movie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22)   A 1000+ Km Road Trip By Bike&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23)   Give a TED Talk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24)  Appear on the Cover of TIME Magazine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a Lot more to Come in Future, if you have any please add them in the Comments Section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please Get in Touch If you Can help me out in any of The Above&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I Always Thought of Putting up a Bucket List of Things I Wanted to Do, And see how Much I can Accomplish.</summary></entry></feed>